BETH: Every individual
with autism is unique.
They may share traits with others,
but the autism spectrum is wide, and
each individual will have their own
outlook and mix of behaviours, many
of which can be really positive.
An individual with autism
can be constantly searching
for a reason or an answer.
This can help them throughout their
education and into their working life.
JOE: Individuals with autism can have
good concentration levels and may
focus on a specific activity for hours.
They can be thorough and have a
high degree of accuracy in what they
do with acute attention to detail.
Individuals with autism’s obsessions
and special interests make them inclined
to thoroughly research things and
find out all they can on a subject.
BETH: They are mainly visual
learners and get used to being able
to see things and reproduce them.
They can spot patterns and repetitions
in things and this can help with
subjects such as science, maths and
music which all are made up of patterns.
JOE: They may also be good at organising
and categorising, and have good memory for
facts and processes, and once they learn
to do something they can repeat it over
and over again without making mistakes.
BETH: They can have creative
and distinctive imaginations and
expression of ideas, and a unique
way of thinking outside the box.
They are often plain speaking and
honest and may be less likely to judge
others, seeing people for what they are.
JOE: Thinking about the positive aspects
of autism can often make life easier
for a parent and change the opinion
of a teacher or potential employer.
It can open doors to new opportunities
and change how individuals with autism
are perceived in the home, school,
employment and in the community.
BETH: Rather than focussing on the
weaknesses associated with autism,
people should focus on the strengths
and the positive aspects of autism.
A positive approach will help to
build good supportive relationships,
which can help with improved
development and quality of life.
Embracing and celebrating a different
way of thinking can help to improve and
add to the world in general and hopefully
make it a more interesting place.